JOSEPH IRABOR

+2348161649497

iraborjoseph063@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-e-irabor/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Joseph is an IT professional with over 6 years of experience in hardware repairs and maintenance, networking, and web development. I have built my expertise in web development as I embarked on projects using web technologies and programming languages. My passion as an IT specialist is built around cyber security and web technology. Consequently, this led me to learn, understand and practice the development of simple to complex digital solutions for the web.

Watchword Privacy and security in cyberspace.

SKILLS

- Programming skills C#, JS, Python, PHP, HTML, CSS, SQL, CMD, Powershell
- Graphics design skills CorelDraw and Figma
- Time management skills
- Team player
- Fluent communication skill
- Critical attention to details

EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2015 – PRESENT

WEB TECHNICIAN, BABCOCK UNIVERSITY HIGH SCHOOL - ILLISAN-REMO, OGUN **STATE**

- Installation and configuration of network end-user devices (Laptops and PC)
- Configuration of network devices (Routers, Switches, WAP, and nano stations) Monitor network for vulnerabilities and define policies along with procedures for users
- Monitor and create updates for the school's website.
- Repair and maintenance of ICT and networking equipment.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Set up a fully functional server room after a fire incident in 2017.
- Design team for the newly launched Babcock university high school website I was able to extend internet connectivity to the staff quarters and its environs • Created a script to flag suspected IP addresses on our network.

SEPTEMBER 2013 – SEPTEMBER 2015

TUTOR (COMPUTER STUDIES), BABCOCK UNIVERSITY HIGH SCHOOL – ILLISAN-REMO, OGUN STATE

Preparation of students for external examination (WAEC and NECO)

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

• Co-presented students for computer studies and data processing in WEAC and NECO which resulted in 100% as all students passed.

MARCH 2011 – SEPTEMBER 2012

DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR (Moodle-Course Management System), BABCOCK UNIVERSITY HIGH SCHOOL – ILLISAN-REMO, OGUN STATE

- Installation and configuration of network resources to support eLearning
- Management of database for the course management system

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Introduced the use of the Moodle course management system.
- Modified the Moodle platform by re-programming it to meet the standard of Babcock university high school.
- Conducted training for staff on the use of the Course management system.

MARCH 2009 – SEPTEMBER 2009

ICT PERSONNEL (INTERNSHIP), NATIONAL PETROLEUM INVESTMENT MANAGEMENT SERVICES – IKOYI, LAGOS STATE

- Installation and configuration of network end-user devices (Laptops and PC) Hardware troubleshooting, repair, and maintenance.
- Helpdesk support.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

• I developed skills in communication and human relations, as I served as the helpdesk

support personnel at the time.

EDUCATION

NOVEMBER 2006 – NOVEMBER 2010

BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE, CARITAS UNIVERSITY, AMORJI-NIKE, ENUGU STATE, NIGERIA

CERTIFICATIONS/TRAINING

NOVEMBER 2021

COMPTIA N+, HIIT-LAGOS

APRIL 2020

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPMENT (Certificate ID: 4ee7506c-3005-4e16-94fc-712219945e03), https://pirple.com



DECEMBER 2016

PROGRAMMING IN MICROSOFT C# (Certificate No:

HIC/2016/7094), HIIT- LAGOS

DECEMBER 2011

CERTIFICATE OF PROFICIENCY IN CCNA, INTRA-METROPOLITAN

TECH-LAGOS

PROJECTS

View projects in digital portfolio here: https://ji-techlab.com.ng

- Built a digital portfolio from scratch.
- Web development team. Babcock University High School's website. I functioned as the layout/UI designer and front-end designer during this project.
- Establish a fully functional server room for Babcock university high school. Designed a transaction control system, a case study of Babcock university high school and currently in use.
- Designed a fully functional website for Ji-TechLAB
- UI/UX prototype/wireframe for CARRYME Logistics using Figma.
- Currently working on a social media app for Babcock university high school.

REFEREES

Available on request